We're going to practice observing
Wir werden eine Übung zur Beobachtung der
the coronal dural sheath in relation to the symphysis and the
koronalen Duralscheide in Bezug auf die Symphyse und in Bezug auf den
maxilla.
Oberkiefer machen.
We'll simply observe how these fields settle, but for that, you'll need to be
Wir werden einfach schauen, wie sich diese Felder setzen, aber dafür müssen Sie sich auf ein
on an electrical level.
elektrisches Niveau begeben.
This is also how we treat tendons, tendinitis.
So behandeln wir auch Sehnen, Sehnenentzündungen.
change many things. As long as you haven't reset
Viele Dinge ändern. Solange Sie die
the electrical currents, it won't work.
elektrischen Ströme nicht wiederhergestellt haben, wird es nicht funktionieren.
And when we see this placement
Und wenn wir diese Einrichtung
of the base of the skull, which is the neurocranium
der Schädelbasis sehen, ist es der Neurokranium
in relation
im Verhältnis
to the viscerocranium. It's as if
zum Viszerokranium. Es ist, als ob
your visceral system was supported
Ihr viszerales System an der
at the base of the skull, like a
Schädelbasis gestützt würde, wie ein
And above,
Und oben
I have my brain
habe ich mein Gehirn,
which is the neurocranium.
das ist der Neurokranium.
And between the two, I have this.
Und dazwischen habe ich das.
And then, I can't
Und dann kann ich nicht
go directly to this base of the skull.
direkt auf diese Schädelbasis gehen.
However, I can reach it through the periphery.
Ich kann aber über die Peripherie dorthin gelangen.
Since we know that all my
Da wir wissen, dass alle meine
dural membranes
Duramembranen
of tension all come
der Spannung alle
to attach to the base of my skull.
an meiner Schädelbasis ansetzen.
They are like moored.
Sie sind wie verankert.
I will first take my
Ich werde zuerst meine
coronal suture and I will take
Koronarnaht nehmen und ich werde den
the part here that we call
Teil hier nehmen, den wir
the maxilla.
Oberkiefer nennen.
Okay?
Okay?
I'm putting myself on that level.
Ich begebe mich auf dieses Niveau.
Maxillo.
Maxillo.
zygomatic, actually, you see.
Jochbein, eigentlich, siehst du.
And I'll be there.
Und ich werde dort sein.
And there, I also have a sheath, actually, that does this.
Und dort habe ich auch eine Scheide, die das macht.
And which also comes, in fact, it's a line that also comes towards the base of the skull.
Und die auch, eigentlich, es ist eine Linie, die auch zur Schädelbasis führt.
They're like rings.
Es sind wie Ringe.
The two rings must meet and be in connection, if you will, you see.
Die beiden Ringe müssen sich treffen und in Verbindung stehen, wenn du so willst, siehst du.
And the electrical level is a subtle level where it's like it's on or off, actually.
Und das elektrische Niveau ist ein subtiles Niveau, wo es wie ein Ein- oder Ausschalten ist, eigentlich.
Don't forget, this coronal suture is quite low, because there are many who are there.
Vergessen Sie nicht, diese Kranznaht ist ziemlich tief, denn es gibt viele, die dort sind.
We're going to go quite well on this coronal suture, where Bregma was.
Wir werden uns ziemlich gut auf diese Kranznaht konzentrieren, dort wo Bregma war.
because if it's alive, there are thermal exchanges
denn wenn es lebt, gibt es thermischen Austausch
there's still a heat that impacts
es gibt eine Wärme, die sich auswirkt
she can also feel it gently
sie kann auch sanft fühlen
there's a point a bit on the line
es gibt einen Punkt etwas auf der Linie
where there's a small energy loss
wo es einen kleinen Energieverlust gibt
there, what you feel
das ist es, was du fühlst
now, I'm going to make you feel
jetzt werde ich dich fühlen lassen
I'm going to put it on the electrical frequency
ich werde auf die elektrische Frequenz gehen
there I put myself on this ring
hier stelle ich mich auf diesen Ring
there I have this connection
hier habe ich diese Verbindung
I go towards this spheno-basilar symphysis
ich gehe zu dieser sphenobasilaren Symphyse
so here I can already say
also kann ich hier schon sagen
look, it's vital, it's warm
schau, das ist vital, das ist warm
responds. There is still a little work that will be done in this
antwortet. Es gibt doch eine kleine Arbeit, die in dieser
movement here, we'll see. I
Bewegung hier stattfinden wird, wir werden sehen. Ich
will now connect with the part of her maxillo-zygomatic
werde mich jetzt mit dem Teil ihres Maxillo-Jochbeins
here, like this,
hier verbinden, so,
which also comes towards... it's as if these two rings meet
der auch zu... es ist, als ob sich diese beiden Ringe treffen
actually. So already between
tatsächlich. Also schon zwischen
the two there is a difference, there is already a bit of a loss at the top, so
den beiden gibt es einen Unterschied, es gibt schon einen Verlust oben, also
there is still a...
es gibt doch eine...
fatigue, there's a struggle. Right away, I'm on her adrenals. Even if I'm
Müdigkeit, es gibt einen Kampf. Sofort bin ich an ihren Nebennieren. Auch wenn ich
here, there's an indirect adrenal connection. So here, we need to recharge the
hier bin, gibt es eine indirekte Nebennierenbeziehung. Also hier muss man die
batteries
Batterien
for madam. For example, here, when I'm there and I feel that in consultation, right
bei der Dame etwas aufladen. Zum Beispiel, wenn ich hier bin und das in der Konsultation spüre, sofort
away, I put myself on her adrenals and I warm up the adrenals. I
stelle ich mich auf ihre Nebennieren und wärme die Nebennieren. Ich
release
löse
the ligaments here and I would put myself like this to recharge
die Bänder hier und ich werde mich so positionieren, um die
the adrenals.
Nebennieren aufzuladen.
Afterwards, we will make the connection with the entire cardiac system,
Danach werden wir die Beziehung zum gesamten Herzsystem herstellen,
so the entire endothelial system,
also zum gesamten Endothelsystem,
how we can work on the four entry points,
wie man an den vier Eintrittspforten arbeiten kann,
which are the left and right internal carotid,
die die linke und rechte innere Halsschlagader sind,
and left and right vertebral, then the basilar system,
und die linke und rechte Wirbelsäulenarterie, dann das Basilarissystem,
with how reactive they are,
wie sie reaktiv sind,
if we touch them correctly,
wenn man sie richtig berührt,
and that we can release them in relation to the heart,
und dass man sie in Bezug auf das Herz befreien kann,
or sometimes in relation to the heart.
oder manchmal in Bezug auf das Herz.
even to the vitelline umbilical system, so mesenteric
sogar zum Nabel-Dottersack-System, also mesenterisch
or splenic on the sinus of the heart.
oder Milz auf dem Sinus des Herzens.
I work with four energies, with the energy of weight or gravity,
Ich arbeite mit vier Energien, mit der Energie der Schwerkraft oder Gravitation,
to restore a proper contact. Either some people are too heavy, they are already buried, or some people are even too light, they float. Then the energy of the midline, then the energy of the energetic body. pure. Here we are more on this electrical plane. What we feel is vibratory. And here again coronal. I wait and then I will see again here. Here again, I already have more vitality. It's not yet 100% but it's already better. There was a void. So it's the hammock of the eye. There, you see, there was a strain. The entire upper axis, so everything was in strain. There, who would that be? Do you feel that? It's as if it made a... I'm exaggerating, but it was like that. When I recognized the tissue, it has its reference point. There is induction. There is movement in ease. I'm not in movement in ease, I'm in presence. OK, first level. Second level, I'm going to work canino, maxillo, three fingers. At the level of my frontal boss. I have an axis like this. I need good support points, otherwise my hand will be unbalanced. There, I feel again. If I feel this warmth and this vibration, and if it's well in the plane. I'm looking for my frontal boss. There, which is here. I look. I stay here. Now, I'm here. There, I take at the same time the line here, and at the same time the line here. You see, the zygomatico-frontal boss line homolateral. So like that, I have two levels. Here, I have a good warmth, I have a good field. Here, it's more diminished. I'm going to look here, at the level of the coronal suture. I'm going to palpate my coronal suture, there, here, there, it's quite, there, here, just a little bit it can block a bit sometimes it makes a canine-maxillary nail here frontal and like that There, it passes. It's not yet how I would like it on the right. I'm looking. As I would like, as... Here, on the other side. Canine, canine. Axillo. Frontal, here, start. And then, here, and there. There's really... It's this axis here that's disturbed. So there's an energy loss here. Maybe it's slower to work. That's why it will heal faster. So here, what I've found each time, it's always in this axis. A bit of a loss of vitality, so to speak. And a bit on the coronal structure that I had a little bit at the beginning that was busy looking. So it's busy rebalancing like that. Third level, which we're doing now, renunciation of flexion. The mastoids. You shouldn't press too hard. There, she has a mastoid, she has a small torsion like that. One is a bit more anterior than the other, if you will. I'm going to see if it's a point of change and balance. And there, I can go into induction or facilitated movement. Here, it's a technique of slight induction. I follow her extension. Oops, she goes into flexion. And I accompany her flexion. And there, I press. When I put myself in these things, here, I observe her breathing. And if I want to go into a point of change, I observe her expiratory pause. Sometimes, people make a... Subtitling Radio-Canada What is that? Change of polarity. They take an inspiration and a big breath. So they make an oxidation, a change of redox.
um einen richtigen Kontakt wiederherzustellen.
pure. Here we are more on this electrical plane. What we feel is vibratory. And
rein. Hier sind wir eher auf dieser elektrischen Ebene. Was wir hier fühlen, ist vibratorisch. Und
here again
hier wieder
coronal. I wait and then I will see again here. Here again,
koronal. Ich warte und werde dann hier noch einmal nachsehen. Hier wieder
I already have more
da habe ich schon mehr
vitality. It's not yet 100% but it's already better. There was a void. So
Vitalität. Es ist noch nicht bei 100%, aber es ist schon besser. Es gab eine Leere. Also
it's the hammock of
ist es die Hängematte des
the eye. There, you see, there was a strain. The entire upper axis,
Auges. Siehst du, da war eine Spannung. Die ganze obere Achse
so everything was in strain.
also alles, was unter Spannung stand.
There, who would that be? Do you feel that?
So, wer wäre das hier? Fühlst du das?
It's as if it made a...
Es ist, als ob es ein...
I'm exaggerating, but it was like that.
Ich übertreibe, aber es war so.
When I recognized the tissue,
Als ich das Gewebe erkannte,
it has its reference point.
hat es seinen Referenzpunkt.
There is induction.
Es gibt die Induktion.
There is movement in ease.
Es gibt die Bewegung in Erleichterung.
I'm not in movement in ease,
Ich bin nicht in der Bewegung in Erleichterung,
I'm in presence.
ich bin in der Präsenz.
OK, first level.
OK, erste Ebene.
Second level, I'm going to work
Zweite Ebene, ich werde arbeiten
canino, maxillo,
canino, maxillot,
three fingers.
drei Finger.
At the level of my frontal boss.
Auf Höhe meines Stirnhöckers.
I have an axis like this.
Ich habe eine solche Achse.
I need good support points,
Ich brauche gute Auflagepunkte,
otherwise my hand will be unbalanced.
sonst gerät meine Hand aus dem Gleichgewicht.
There, I feel again.
Hier spüre ich es wieder.
If I feel this warmth and this vibration,
Wenn ich diese Wärme und diese Vibration spüre,
and if it's well in the plane.
und wenn es gut in der Ebene ist.
I'm looking for my frontal boss.
Ich suche meinen Stirnhöcker.
There, which is here.
So, der ist hier.
I look.
Ich schaue.
I stay here.
Ich bleibe hier.
Now, I'm here.
Jetzt bin ich hier.
There, I take at the same time the line here,
Dort nehme ich gleichzeitig die Linie hier,
and at the same time the line here.
und gleichzeitig die Linie hier.
You see, the zygomatico-frontal boss line
Du siehst, die zygomatisch-frontale Höckerlinie
homolateral.
ipsilateral.
So like that, I have two levels.
So habe ich zwei Ebenen.
Here, I have a good warmth, I have a good field.
Hier habe ich eine gute Wärme, ein gutes Feld.
Here, it's more diminished.
Hier ist es stärker reduziert.
I'm going to look here, at the level of the coronal suture.
Ich werde hier am Koronarnaht nachsehen.
I'm going to palpate my coronal suture, there, here, there,
Ich werde meine Koronarnaht hier abtasten,
it's quite, there, here, just a little bit
es ist ziemlich, hier ein ganz kleines bisschen
it can block a bit
es kann ein bisschen blockieren
sometimes it makes a canine-maxillary nail
manchmal macht es einen Eckzahn-Oberkiefer-Klick
here frontal and like that
hier frontal und so
There, it passes.
So, es geht.
It's not yet how I would like it on the right.
Es ist noch nicht so, wie ich es rechts haben möchte.
I'm looking.
Ich suche.
As I would like, as...
Wie ich es möchte, wie...
Here, on the other side.
Hier, auf der anderen Seite.
Canine, canine.
Eckzahn, Eckzahn.
Axillo.
Achsel.
Frontal, here, start.
Frontal, hier, Start.
And then, here, and there.
Und dann, hier, und dort.
There's really...
Es gibt wirklich...
It's this axis here that's disturbed.
Es ist diese Achse hier, die gestört ist.
So there's an energy loss here.
Es gibt also einen Energieverlust hier.
Maybe it's slower to work.
Vielleicht ist es langsamer zu bearbeiten.
That's why it will heal faster.
Deshalb wird es schneller heilen.
So here, what I've found each time, it's always in this axis.
Was ich hier jedes Mal gefunden habe, war jedes Mal in dieser Achse.
A bit of a loss of vitality, so to speak.
Ein kleiner Vitalitätsverlust, in Anführungszeichen.
And a bit on the coronal structure that I had a little bit
Und ein bisschen an der Koronarstruktur, die ich ein bisschen
at the beginning that was busy looking.
am Anfang gesucht hatte.
So it's busy rebalancing like that.
Es ist also dabei, sich so wieder ins Gleichgewicht zu bringen.
Third level, which we're doing now,
Dritte Ebene, die wir jetzt machen,
renunciation of flexion.
Verzicht auf die Flexion.
The mastoids.
Die Mastoiden.
You shouldn't press too hard.
Man darf nicht zu stark drücken.
There, she has a mastoid, she has a small torsion like that.
So, sie hat einen Mastoid, sie hat eine kleine Torsion so.
One is a bit more anterior than the other, if you will.
Einer ist etwas anteriorer als der andere, wenn du so willst.
I'm going to see if it's a point of change and balance.
Ich werde sehen, ob es ein Punkt der Veränderung und des Gleichgewichts ist.
And there, I can go into induction or facilitated movement.
Und dort kann ich in die Induktion oder in die erleichterte Bewegung gehen.
Here, it's a technique of slight induction.
Hier ist eine leichte Induktionstechnik.
I follow her extension.
Ich bin ihre Verlängerung.
Oops, she goes into flexion.
Hopp, sie geht in Flexion.
And I accompany her flexion.
Und ich begleite ihre Flexion.
And there, I press.
Und da drücke ich.
When I put myself in these things, here,
Wenn ich mich in diese Dinge begebe, hier,
I observe her breathing.
beobachte ich ihre Atmung.
And if I want to go into a point of change,
Und wenn ich zu einem Wendepunkt gelangen möchte,
I observe her expiratory pause.
beobachte ich ihre exspiratorische Atempause.
Sometimes, people make a...
Manchmal machen die Leute eine...
Subtitling Radio-Canada
Untertitelung Société Radio-Canada
What is that?
Was ist das?
Change of polarity.
Polaritätswechsel.
They take an inspiration and a big breath.
Sie atmen ein und atmen tief aus.
So they make an oxidation, a change of redox.
Sie machen also eine Oxidation, eine Redoxreaktion.